Kenneth Wardlow

Full-stack web developer using my experience in team leadership with robotic technologies to build a better experience for end users. Previous work involved being constantly challenged with ways to make are companies remotely operated vehicles perform tasks the customer needed. Recently earned a certificate in full-stack web development from the University of Texas Austin, Strong passion for problem solving and turning new ideas into realities. Currently looking forward to using what I have learned to dive into new and engaging problems and ideas to build better experiences on the web and to always be enhancing or creating something new

EXPERIENCE

Team Industrial, Alvin, Tx — NDT Technician Level 2

August 2019 - PRESENT

Perform Quality control inspections in various chemical plants and oil and gas industry.
Throughout the country

Dow Chemical, Freeport, Tx — Sr. Maintenance Robotics technologist, M&E

September 2017 - May 2019

- Help implement and create their still functioning robotic department.
- Trained employees throughout North America and Canada on the use and operation of this new technology and equipment.
- Modifying the robotic capabilities to perform tasks not originally intended by design
- Saved the company Annually 50 million in time lost for shutdown operations.

Southern Technical Services, Freeport, Tx — NDT Technician Level 2

October 2013 - September 2017

 Performed Quality control inspections as in current job while creating their robotic department for Dow Chemical. And other companies they were contracted with.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas, Austin —Full-Stack web development

Certificate in Full Stack Web development

Austin Community College, Austin, Tx — Studied business and computer science

Relevant Coursework

Studied business management and computer Science

Brazosport Community College, Lake Jackson Tx — General studies

Relevant Coursework

General Studies and Computer Science

PROJECTS

BarMaid Web Application--Git Repository | Deployed Project

Simple web application for finding your favorite drinks. Providing instructions, ingredients and measurements. Uses geolocation for locating liquor stores with links to google maps for directions. Provided back end development with API's to bring the information client side as well as all styling

Scope Web application-Git Repository | Deployed Project

Horoscope App that allows users to create an account linked to their info pulling specific info from one of our API's to provide them with a 3 day horoscope forecast and a compatibility page. Worked on developing the models for account authentication and database storing structure to pull appropriate API data. Also created the page for compatibility results using a separate API and styling of the page .

Lake Jackson, Tx 77566

(979) 292-4562

Kenneth@wardlowservices.com

LinkedIn

Github Profile

Portfolio

SKILLS

- Computer Science applied to JavaScript
- Design Patterns
- Algorithms
- Browser Based Technologies
- + HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Responsive Design
- Bootstrap
- Handlebars
- Cookies, Local Storage
- React.js
- Deployment
- • Heroku
- Git
- Databases
- MySQL
- • MongoDB
- Server-Side Development
- Express
- Security and Session Storage
- User Authentication
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)
- Quality Assurance
- Writing Tests
- Internet Marketing
- Semantic HTML

Certificate

Full-Stack Web Development